#### ANURAG GUPTA

Bengaluru, KA India

Mobile: +91 998 656 8434

Email: anuraggupta.hits@gmail.com

Website: anuraggupta.in

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Principal front-end developer with 7+ years of experience designing and building responsive web design and mobile apps in the financial industry. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 90% with improved code and design.

#### **SKILLS**

*	JavaScript
*	ReactJs
*	VueJs

- Angular TypeScript
- HTML5
- CSS3/SCSS Bootstrap ❖ Ionic/React

❖ React Redux

- ❖ NPM
- Nodeis
- Git GitHub
- Gulp

- Grunt
- SQL Basics / SSMS
- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Microsoft Fluent UI
- Syncfusion Controls

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Principal Software Engineer @ Innominds Software, India **Senior Software Engineer Software Engineer**

- Built a dynamic user-interface designer studio for users to let them create or update any forms like dashboards, reports, and forms with different types of controls such as Toggle Buttons, Checkboxes, Input Controls, Search Box, Tables, Charts, Advanced Search Controls, and 20+ other types of controls as desired for different customers. These controls have numerous properties that can be added and updated for different requirements This kind of design brought in new customers for our client Vector Flow.
- Practicing Generic Programming, futuristic viewing and thinking out of the box to provide new enhanced features for generic components using existing UI designers with very less effort.
- ❖ Created more than 100+ different types of forms, dashboards and reports that helped represent data making all users' interaction with data easier.
- Collaborated with UX/UI design teams to improve the website and applications, increasing conversion rates by 60%.
- Mentored associates and peers with problem-solving approaches and project walk-throughs.
- Strategize with senior management to discuss the challenges and timeline for different requirements in an agile web development environment.
- Developed testable, reusable, efficient, and legible code for enhancements.

# Apr 2021 - Till now **Apr 2020 - Mar 2021** Mar 2019 - Mar 2020

**Technology Used** ReactJs **JavaScript** Angular 2+ **Typescript** HTML5 CSS3. **SCSS Bootstrap** SOL **Nodels** 

## Senior System Engineer @ Infosys Ltd, India

- Built numerous standard generic components and dashboards which helped read consolidated data and interact with the data.
- Received training and certification in Advance Angular through the Infosys Lex program.
- Mentored the associates and peers and collaborated with them to get desired work done.
- \* Received training and certification in Infosys Global Agile Developer Certification which helped me achieve my target user stories.

#### Mar 2018 - Feb 2019

Technology Used Angular 2+ **Typescript JavaScript** Reactis HTML5

> CSS3/SCSS **Bootstrap**

Soft	ware Engineer @ <u>HireCraft Software Pvt Ltd, India</u>	Oct 2016 – Jan 2018
Asso	ciate Software Engineer	Oct 2015 – Sept 2016
	ccountable for solving complex problems based on designs and functionalities uch as tree structure, multiple files upload, excel export etc.	Technology Used <b>Angular</b>
	uilt numerous reusable generic components and directives keeping end-users' erspectives in mind and making it user interactive.	React JavaScript
	uilt numerous career portals for different customers and was well appreciated or the work.	HTML5 CSS3, SCSS
	ravelled to client locations and worked directly with their team for a better inderstanding of the requirements and time constraints.	Bootstrap Grunt/Gulp

### **PROJECTS**

## SOCs Management - Vector Flow @ Innominds Software Pvt Ltd

Jan 2020 – Till Now

Vector Flow is dedicated to using machine learning and automation to deliver improved operational efficiencies – and effectiveness – across the entire physical security domain. Vector Flow's SOC management software is a system whereby organizations keep track of their staff, contractors, visitors, and other relevant people, and control their access to facilities, areas within facilities, and/or other assets.

### PIAM - HID Global @ Innominds Software Pvt Ltd

Mar 2019 – Jan 2020

Physical Identity and Access Management (PIAM) breaks down traditional organizational silos to transform communities of stakeholders involved in identity management such as employees and contractors, security departments and process managers in HR, IT, Facilities, Reception, Contractor Administration, etc. Everyday millions of people in more than 100 countries use our products and services to securely access physical and digital places.

#### My Cisco Entitlements (MCE) - Cisco @ Infosys Ltd

Mar 2018 - Feb 2019

My Cisco Entitlements (MCE) is a secure one-stop platform where you can gain insights into your business and better manage your Cisco products and services to minimize risk. Here you can centrally organize all your Cisco services, subscriptions, licenses, and devices in one place.

Stakeholders: Cisco Customers and Partners.

#### **TALLINT™ Enterprise @ HireCraft Software Pvt Ltd**

Mar 2015 - Feb 2018

Designed for leaders in Talent centric business organizations like Consulting, IT/ITES, Engineering, Construction, Research, or any other industry where talent management is critical. TALLINT™ defines the way forward to help you manage your sales force automation, talent acquisition, workforce provisioning, project management, and project profitability management in real time.

#### **EDUCATION**

♦ Bachelors in Engineer in Computer Science in the year 2014 from Hindustan University Chennai, TN, India.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- ❖ Promoted to Principal Engineer at Innominds Software Pvt. Ltd., Bengaluru, KA, India for exceptional work performance in the year 2021.
- Accoladed with InnoStar award at Innominds Software Pvt Ltd for excellence in performance in the year 2021.
- ❖ Promoted to Senior Software Engineer at Innominds Software Pvt. Ltd., Bengaluru, KA, India for exceptional work performance within a year of joining the company in the year 2020.
- Awarded twice in dance competitions at Yarona 2012 & 2013 conducted by Hindustan University, Chennai, TN, India.
- Awarded Gold Medals for In-house Basketball Tournaments at S.J.D.A.V. Public School, Jharkhand, India.